<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Workflows on </title>
    <link>/workflows/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Workflows on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Core Bioinformatics and Informatics Group</copyright><atom:link href="/workflows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Short Read Metagenomics</title>
      <link>/workflows/metagenomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/workflows/metagenomics/</guid>
      <description>This version is built with Go 1.21.1 which contains some relevant security fixes for the html/template package, see Issue 62196 and Issue 62197. This is the main reason Hugo 0.119.0 is released sooner rather than later. But this release also comes with a dependency refresh and some useful image processing improvements:
A new general-purpose Process method and filter. A new Opacity filter.
Release Notes on GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>De-novo assembly long read</title>
      <link>/workflows/long-read-assembly/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/workflows/long-read-assembly/</guid>
      <description>This is pseudo content generated by ChatGPT. De-novo Assembly for Long Read Nanopore Data De-novo assembly refers to the process of assembling genomes from scratch, without the use of a reference genome. This is particularly useful for studying novel organisms or strains. Long-read sequencing technologies, such as Oxford Nanopore, provide reads that are much longer than those generated by short-read technologies, allowing for more accurate and contiguous genome assemblies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taxonomic Profiling</title>
      <link>/workflows/taxonomic-profiling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/workflows/taxonomic-profiling/</guid>
      <description>Workflow Summary This workflow is designed for metagenomic profiling, involving steps for quality control, taxonomic classification, and data retrieval:
Input dataset collection:
The workflow starts with an input dataset collection, which is likely to be a set of sequencing reads. Kraken2:
A tool for taxonomic classification, which assigns taxonomic labels to short DNA sequences. Fastp:
A tool for fast all-in-one preprocessing for FastQ files, including quality control and read trimming.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
